http://www.liverpoolwarmuseum.co.uk/privacy-policy

Privacy Policy – Western Approaches
Skip to content
Get updates
Search for:
Sunday - 10am - 5pm
Last entry 4pm.
We will be closed from 5pm on 23rd December, reopening on 2nd January 2021.
Sunday - 10am - 5pm
Last entry 4pm.
We will be closed from 5pm on 23rd December, reopening on 2nd January 2021.
Close
Sign up to our newsletter
Stay up to date with the latest news, new exhibits, competitions, surveys, fundraising activities, and exclusive late night events!Email*
Name
First
Last
GroupsWhich updates would you like to recieve?
Western Approaches, Liverpool
Chester: A Life Story
Big Heritage
Consent* By checking this box you are consenting to receive marketing emails from us. We will never sell or share your personal details to third parties for the purposes of marketing. For more information see our
privacy policy.PhoneThis field is for validation purposes and should be left unchanged.
This iframe contains the logic required to handle Ajax powered Gravity Forms.
Privacy Policy
Who we are
Western Approaches is a unique experience that tells the story of Derby House in Liverpool and its strategic role in the second world war.
The site is in the custodianship of Big Heritage, a registered Community Interest Company.
We are registered as a data controller under the Data Protection Act 1998, and our Data Protection Registration Number is: Z159876X.
Introduction
We hold information about you to provide you with a better service from Western Approaches and to ensure that we understand how Western Approaches is fulfilling its objectives of delivering an enjoyable visitor experience and engaging people in the past for positive change.
Developing a better understanding of our visitors and supporters through their personal data allows us to make better decisions. We will only send marketing communications to those that have explicitly stated that they are happy for us to do so via their preferred channel(s) (email, SMS, phone or post).
Where we collect personal information that can identify you
Ticket sales made online for individual or group bookings
By subscribing to our newsletter
Emails or correspondence sent to us
Donation forms (artefacts and oral histories)
CCTV – we use CCTV onsite at Western Approaches to ensure the security of our staff and comply, where relevant, with licensing laws
What personal data we collect and how we use it
The type and quantity of information we collect and how we use it depends on why you are providing it.
Visitors
If you book as an individual or a group online via our website, we will collect all or some of the following data:
Name
Address
Email
Telephone number
Type of tickets purchased and date of planned visit
Date of birth
Gender
Contact preferences
Type of organisation (group booking only)
Size of group (group booking only)
Marketing emails
If you subscribe to our newsletter we will collect all or some of the following data:
Name
Postcode
Email
Telephone number
Date of Birth
Gender
Contact preferences
Correspondence sent to us
If you contact us to provide feedback or make a query, or ask us to do something, we will collect all or some of the following data:
Reason for contact and our response
Name
Email
Address
Donations
If you choose to donate an item or your oral history relating to the stories of wartime Liverpool, then we will collect the following data:
Item being donated
Donor name
Donor address
Background/history of donated item
In the case of an oral history, we will collect the donor’s date of birth, and a separate oral history consent form will be provided
How we use your data
We will mainly use your data to:
Provide you with the services, products or information you have asked for
Understand our visitors and wider audience to improve the venue, its events, products and services
Keep a record of your relationship with us
Ensure we know how you prefer to be contacted
We also use data to improve Western Approaches, and understand the needs of our visitors. To do this, we may combine your personal data with information from organisations such as Audience Agency, to better understand the interests and requirements of our visitors.
We will only hold your personal information for as long as is necessary to ensure we manage your pre and post visit experience effectively, or to provide the service you have subscribed to.
Direct Marketing
Under The General Data Protection Regulations 2016/679 (GDPR), we will only send you marketing communications with your consent. In the case of our newsletters, a check box must be ticked by the visitor and the ‘SEND’ button clicked.
Once consent is gained, we will contact you to keep you up to date with the latest news and events, and to ask you to take part in surveys, ask for donations, or other support. We will always include information on how to opt out of these communications.
Unsubscribe from marketing emails
You can unsubscribe from our marketing emails at any time by clicking the Unsubscribe link that is at the bottom of every email, or by emailing info@westernapproaches.org.uk to request to be removed. Please allow 48 hours for your preferences to be updated.
Use of Cookies
This website uses cookies to better the users experience while visiting the website. Where applicable this website uses a cookie control system allowing the user on their first visit to the website to allow or disallow the use of cookies on their computer / device. This complies with legislation requirements for websites to obtain explicit consent from users before leaving behind or reading files such as cookies on a user’s computer/device.
Cookies are small files saved to the user’s computer’s hard drive that track, save and store information about the user’s interactions and usage of the website. This allows the website, through its server, to provide the users with a tailored experience within this website.
Users are advised that if they wish to deny the use and saving of cookies from this website on to their computers hard drive they should take necessary steps within their web browsers security settings to block all cookies from this website and its external serving vendors.
This website uses tracking software to monitor its visitors to better understand how they use it. This software is provided by Google Analytics which uses cookies to track visitor usage. The software will save a cookie to your computer’s hard drive in order to track and monitor your engagement and usage of the website but will not store, save or collect personal information. You can read Google’s privacy policy for further information.
Other cookies may be stored to your computer’s hard drive by external vendors when this website uses referral programs, sponsored links or adverts. Such cookies are used for conversion and referral tracking and typically expire after 30 days, though some may take longer. No personal information is stored, saved or collected.
How we keep your data safe
We ensure that there are appropriate technical and policy and process controls in place to protect your personal details
We undertake regular reviews of who has access to information that we hold to ensure that your information is only accessible by appropriately trained staff.
Some of our suppliers run their operations outside the European Economic Area (EEA). Although they may not be subject to same data protection laws as companies based in the UK, we will take steps to ensure they provide an adequate level of protection in accordance with UK data protection law. By submitting your personal information to us you agree to this transfer, storing or processing at a location outside the EEA.
Keeping Your Information Up to Date
Please notify us if your personal information changes.
Your right to know what we know about you, make changes or ask us to stop using your information
You have a right to ask us to stop processing your personal data, and if it’s not necessary for the purpose you provided it to us for (e.g. registering you for an event, processing ticket sales) we will do so. Contact us on info@westernapproaches.org.uk if you have any queries or concerns.
You have a right to ask for a copy of the information we hold about you If there are any discrepancies in the information we provide, please let us know and we will correct them.
If you want to access your information, please send this request and proof of your identity by post to Operations Director (SAR), Western Approaches C/O Big Heritage, 15A Watergate Row, Chester, CH1 2LE. We do not accept these requests by email so we can ensure that we only provide personal data to the right person.
Find out more
Name
First name
Last name
Email*
Message
Want to receive our marketing newsletters?
By checking this box you are consenting to receive marketing emails from us. We will never sell or share your personal details to third parties for the purposes of marketing. For more information see our
privacy policy.GroupsWhich updates would you like to receive?
Western Approches, Liverpool
Chester: A Life Story
Big Heritage
Oops! You need to tick at least one if you want to receive updates.CAPTCHAPhoneThis field is for validation purposes and should be left unchanged.
This iframe contains the logic required to handle Ajax powered Gravity Forms.
Western Approaches Museum, 1-3 Rumford Street, Exchange Flags, Liverpool L2 8SZ
It's a Reasonably Good Website
